Dreadwing. Damage report.
骇翼 损伤报告？
We have suffered critical damage to all major systems, lord Megatron.
所有重要系统都严重受损 威震天陛下
It will be some time before we can get the ship airborne.
需要一段时间才能让飞船重新起飞
Soundwave.
声波…
So it was an Autobot who crippled my vessel.
看来是一个汽车人弄坏了我的船
They will move quickly to exploit any perceived weakness.
他们必定会抓住我们的破绽 发起奇袭
Surely they're not foolish enough to launch a direct assault, my liege.
他们显然不会蠢到发动正面攻击吧 我的君王？
Optimus has grown decidedly more ruthless since our last encounter.
自从我们上次见面后 擎天柱不再那么心慈手软了…
Lord Megatron, as your physician,
威震天陛下 作为您的医生
I strongly advice against this.
对此我表示强烈反对
Dark Energon's regenerative properties are impressive,
尽管黑暗能量的再生能力十分可观
but the side effects...
但这副作用…
there is no telling how it might impact the ship.
我们无从得知它会对飞船造成什么伤害
Dark Energon courses through my veins.
黑暗能量就在我身体中流淌
Infusing the warship will enable me to manipulate the craft as if we are one.
把它输给战舰将使我能操纵战舰
And together, we shall crush Optimus Prime.
我们合二为一 便可摧毁擎天柱
But when the Insecticons suddenly backed off,
那些机器昆虫突然退下了
I got inspired by my proximity to the power core...
我意识到我应该离动力核心很近
... and did what I do best.
于是我发挥特长…
You trashed Megatron's ride like a rock star in a hotel room.
你把威震天的飞船搞得一团糟 简直就像旅馆房间里的摇滚明星！
We should hit the Cons right now while they're vulnerable.
我们应该乘虚而入 发动进攻
Megatron's warship may be grounded,
尽管威震天的飞船迫降了
but let's not forget that we remain vastly outnumbered.
但别忘了对手的人数是我们的几百倍
Especially since he has added the insecticon hive to his ranks.
特别是他又把一窝虫子收入麾下…
Then maybe it's time for me to call in an air strike.
要不我呼叫空中打击吧
Or for us to consider more extreme measures, Agent Fowler.
或许我们应该考虑一些非常手段 福勒探员
The Spark extractor?
火种剥离器？
Optimus, are you certain you want to travel down this path?
擎天柱 你确定要这么做？
While I am deeply reluctant to deploy a weapon of this caliber,
虽然我十分不情愿动用这种武器
especially one forged by Decepticon hands,
尤其是霸天虎设计的武器…
this may be our only chance to end the war
…但这或许是我们结束战争的唯一办法…
once and for all.
…一劳永逸
Yes. I can feel it!
是的 我感觉得到！
Optimus, I'm detecting a massive energy spike at the Decepticon crash site.
擎天柱 我在霸天虎的坠机处监测到一个巨大的能量信号！
It appears to be dark Energon.
那是黑暗能量
Autobots, transform and roll out!
汽车人 变形出发！
Hold on, Prime. If you are gonna deploy some kind of super weapon in the final showdown with the Cons,
等等 擎天柱 既然你要使用超级武器 来与霸天虎作最终决战
it's my job as a representative of planet Earth to bear witness.
那么 我有义务代表地球人见证这一刻！
Sweet lady Liberty.
我的自由女神像啊！
Optimus, you never disappoint.
擎天柱 你从不辜负我的期待
Bumblebee, now.
大黄蜂 趁现在！
Arcee, Bulkhead, draw their fire.
阿尔茜 隔板 吸引火力！
Once you launch the Spark extractor,
一旦启动火种剥离器
be sure to clear its radius before it can activate.
立即撤出其有效半径
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
Mine!
我来！
I didn't realize this ship was equipped with a stasis beam.
我怎么不知道舰上配备了静止射线！
So much for christmas in Fiji.
去斐济过圣诞节的愿望要泡汤了
Huh?
嗯？
The Spark extractor!
火种剥离器
Guide us closer so that I may collect what belongs to me
靠近点 让我取回本属于我的东西
and destroy the Autobots.
然后摧毁汽车人！
Team's down. Requesting medevac.
作战失败 呼叫医疗救援
What?! Where are you going? I said closer!
什么？你要去哪儿？我说靠近！
Lord Megatron, the ship seems to be navigating itself.
威震天陛下 飞船看上去像在自动驾驶
Override.
手动操控！
The system's are bypassing manual contr... ohhh!
系统不接受手动控制！
It appears the ship now possesses a will of its own.
看上去飞船有了自己的意识！
Impossible!
不可能！
Trace the problem to its source and fix it!
查出故障原因 然后修好它！
Do not tamper with my systems!
不许篡改我的系统
This will be your only warning!
我只警告一次！
Warning?!
警告？！
My mission assumes priority.
我的任务优先执行
Any Cybertronian who interferes will be neutralized.
任何干扰我的塞博特恩人都将被摧毁…
My own vessel dares to address me in threatening tones?!
我自己的飞船竟敢用威胁的口吻和我说话？
It also seems to be doing a better job of decoding the project Iacon database than we were.
而且它似乎比我们更擅长破译铁堡计划的数据库
It's already deciphered a new set of coordinates.
它已经又解出了一组坐标！
And judging by our current course,
按我们目前的航向推断
that is precisely where the ship is headed.
那正是战舰要去的地方
As I desire. You see,
那正是我想要的 你看
this warship is nothing more than an extension of my very will.
这艘战舰不过是我个人意志的延伸
Your will is nothing.
你的个人意志不值一提！
The Iacon artifact will belong to me.
铁堡的遗产将属于我！
I am Lord Megatron! I command you to cease operations!
我是威震天陛下！我命令你停止运行！
You are no longer in command.
你权威不再了
Regain control of this vessel
不管用什么手段
by any means necessary.
夺回战舰的控制权！
All hands, cut power to the mainframe
全体船员 切断主能源
and disconnect data relays now!
断开数据继电器 马上行动！
They're alive.
他们还活着
But I've never encountered this form of stasis lock.
但我从没遇到过这种类型的静止状态
The 'cons are crossing the Atlantic,
虎子们正在穿越大西洋！
making a beeline for North America.
沿着最短的路线前往北美地区！
Wait. We can track them?
等等 我们能追踪他们？
Why aren't they cloaked, like usual?
他们为什么没有照常开启隐形装置？
None of this makes a lick of sense.
一切都太不正常了
They had us in their cross hairs, but the 'Cons just took off.
他们离我们近在咫尺 却转身飞走了！
They even bailed on that Spark extractor thingy.
他们连火种剥离器都没拿！
Well, if the ship isn't cloaked,
如果飞船没有隐形
maybe the communications relay's open,
或许通讯频道也开着 那么…
- and... - Yep, yep. Are you suggesting that we just call Megatron
怎么着 你的意思是咱干脆给老威打个电话
and ask him what's happening up there?!
问问他上面发生了什么？
Lord Megatron, the computer has decrypted a second set of coordinates.
威震天陛下 计算机破解了另一个坐标
Perhaps we should permit it to continue.
或许我们应该允许它继续…
I do not require permission.
我不需要谁的准许
Autobot outpost Omega One to Decepticon warship.
汽车人基地欧米伽一号呼叫霸天虎战舰！
Megatron, please respond.
威震天 请回话
This mutiny ends now.
这场叛变到此为止了！
Megatron.
威震天
Megatron has been relieved of his command.
威震天已被革除了领导地位
Who is this?
你是谁？
Who is this?!
你是谁！
Have you taken control of the Decepticon vessel?
你控制了霸天虎战舰？
I am the vessel.
我就是战舰！
Any Cybertronian who interferes with my mission will be neutralized.
任何敢于干涉我任务的塞博特恩人都将被摧毁
What mission?
什么任务？
Priority one
首要任务
decrypt Iacon database and recover Decepticon technology.
破译铁堡数据库 回收霸天虎科技
For what purpose?
为了什么目的？
It hung up? Rude.
它挂机了？不礼貌！
Rude?! There's a giant spaceship flying around
岂止不礼貌？一艘巨大的战舰在四处游荡
collecting Decepticon weapons of mass destruction!
搜集霸天虎的大规模杀伤性武器！
Wha... a giant spaceship filled with neutralized Decepticons.
这艘巨大战舰上的霸天虎都被消灭了
Point?
什么意思？
This could be our only chance to slip aboard and download the Iacon database.
这或许是我们登舰下载铁堡数据库的唯一机会
So Optimus can decode it.
这样擎天柱就能破译它！
Ingenious. I will infiltrate the Decepticon warship.
绝妙的主意 我会潜入霸天虎的飞船
Not ingenious. You saw what it did to the Decepticons.
这样就不妙了 霸天虎是什么下场你都看到了
And probably Megatron, too.
说不定威震天都难保！
And team Prime.
还有领袖卫队
But that tub had me dead to rights,
不过？那艘战舰明明可以置我于死地
and I'm still breathing.
我却保住了老命！
The ship may be blind to humans.
那艘船或许看不到人类
Very well, Agent Fowler.
很好 福勒探员
But at the first sign of trouble,
不过一旦有任何险情
I am bridging you right back here.
我会立即将你传送回来！
Now, in order to download the database,
现在 为了下载数据
you will need a compatible transfer drive.
你需要一个相匹配的传输磁盘
A what?
什么？
He'll also need tech support.
他还需要技术支持
And backup.
还有后援！
Fowler to base. We're in.
福勒呼叫基地 我们进来了
Good. Their data core should be accessible from any console.
很好 任意一个控制台都可以访问数据核心
H-here's one.
这…这儿有一个！
Doc Knock is knocked out.
击倒被击倒了！
Look. The ship's decoded two sets of Iacon coordinates.
看 战舰解出了两组铁堡坐标！
Three! Let's rip and run.
三个！咱们赶快拿了闪人
There's the port.
这里是接口！
Um, why is the warship heading for Manhattan?
嗯 为什么这艘战舰在飞向曼哈顿？
Because that is where first set of coordinates are located.
因为那里是第一组坐标锁定的地点？
What would a relic from Cybertron be doing in the Big Apple?
塞博特恩的遗物怎么可能在美国纽约城？
The Iacon relics landed on Earth eons ago, Agent Fowler,
铁堡的圣物在很久以前失落到了地球上 福勒探员
long before the city was built atop it.
远早于城市建立的时间
Which means if the ship wants this one...
也就是说战舰为了得到这个
it may have to move some buildings out of the way.
得推掉一些大楼
Our mission just got complicated.
我们的任务变得复杂了
How do we deter this ship?
我们要怎么阻止战舰？
I would advise disabling the navigation module.
我建议销毁导航模块
Call up the main navigation menu.
调出主导航菜单！
There.
那里！
Step aside, son.
让开 孩子！
Agent Fowler!
福勒探员？！
System access detected.
发现系统访问
Interference will not be tolerated.
严禁任何干涉行为！
There.
那边！
Reveal yourself.
快现身！
It doesn't see us.
它没有看到我们！
Yet.
暂时的！
The ship must not be scanning for carbon-based life-forms.
战舰没有扫描碳基生命体
But once it widens its search parameters...
但是一旦它扩大搜索频率…
We're toast.
我们就完蛋了
I'm bridging you back.
我把你们传送回来！
No. There are millions of lives at stake in New York,
不！纽约成千上万的生命正在生死关头
and we three are currently the only ones who can do anything about it.
而我们三个是唯一可以阻止这件事的人
You're out of your element, Jack.
别勉强自己 杰克
These readings, the ship's rapid recovery...
从读数上看 还有战舰恢复的速度
all point to the fact that Megatron employed Dark Energon to repair it.
都说明威震天用了黑暗能量来修复它
Hold on. If you're saying the ship is fueled by dark Energon,
等等 如果说战舰是靠黑暗能量驱动的
we can dump it, right?
那我们可以切断供给 不是吗？
You'll need to reserve the warship's Energon infuser.
嗯…你们需要关闭战舰的能量注入器
Follow the main overhead conduits.
顺着天花板上的主管道前进
They'll lead you to the power core.
就能到达能量核心
Megatron had the same idea.
威震天也准备这么干！
Then we're on the right track.
这么说我们走对了
The Energon injection valve can only be operated manually.
能量输出闸门只能手动操作
- Manually?!
手动？
Give me a boost.
托我上去！
I am infested with alien life-forms!
我被外星生命体入侵了！
Uh-Oh. We just got made.
啊哦 我们完了！
All parasites will be eradicated!
清除一切寄生虫
Hey! Over here!
嘿！这里！
Jack, no!
杰克 不！
Run for it!
快跑！
Too slow!
太慢了！
Critical power drain.
动力严重不足
I am... in... command.
我…才是…老大！
Prepare to be...
准备…
neutralized.
受死…
Run.
快跑
Thank the Allspark.
感谢火种源
Ratchet!
救护车
Fire up the Ground Bridge!
开启环陆桥！
On your feet, soldier.
站稳了 士兵！
And beavers and ducks and walnuts and... grandma?
还有海狸还有海象还有鸭子还有老奶奶！
That's all that's been downloaded?!
才下载了这么点？
The Iacon file must be huge!
铁堡档案肯定很庞大！
Sa-weet!
太棒了！
Come on! Here's our ride!
快 我们快走！
Jack?!
杰克？
Get Fowler out of here.
送福勒出去
Some is better than nothing.
有一点总比什么都没有强
I'm not leaving without that drive.
拿不到磁盘我是不会走的
Say "ahh."
说“啊”
I'm here to offer a second opinion.
我来提点不同的诊断意见
Lord Megatron, I...
威震天陛下 我…
You let them escape...
你让他们跑了！
with vital intelgence.
还带着重要的情报！
The download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete,
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
Then we must act quickly,
那我们必须得尽快行动
for Megatron possesses the same four sets.
因为威震天也有这四个坐标
And he will not hesitate to obtain the potential doomsday devices which lie at the site of each.
并且 他会毫不犹豫地夺取那里的超级武器…